Guide to the Portland Brewing Company Records 1984-2021
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections and Archives Research Center
Portland Brewing Company Records
1984-2021
1993-2021
Portland Brewing Company.
MSS PortlandBrewing
10.00 cubic feet, including 85 photographs 11 boxes, including 1 oversize box, and 1 map folder
Special Collections and Archives Research Center 121 The Valley Library Oregon State University Corvallis, OR, 97331-4501 Phone: 541-737-2075 Email: scarc@oregonstate.edu Web: http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/findingaids
The Portland Brewing Company Records includes brewing records, photographs, promotional and training materials, and ephemera. The Portland Brewing Company was incorporated by Fred Bowman and Art Larrance in 1983; it opened in 1986. Hart Brewing was founded by Beth Hartwell and Tom Baune in Kalama, Washington in 1984; the name was changed to Pyramid Breweries in 1996. The Portland brewery facility closed in 2021. At various points, these companies merged and purchased by other companies.
Historical Note:
The Portland Brewing Company was incorporated by Fred Bowman and Art Larrance in 1983; it opened in 1986. Hart Brewing was founded by Beth Hartwell and Tom Baune in Kalama, Washington in 1984; the name was changed to Pyramid Breweries in 1996. The Portland brewery facility closed in 2021. At various points, these companies merged and purchased by other companies.
Portland Brewing Company
The Portland Brewing Company was incorporated by Fred Bowman and Art Larrance in 1983. Bert Grant, owner of Yakima Brewing Company, was hired in 1985 as a technical consultant to assist in designing the brewhouse. The company was initially funded by a small public offering in 1985 that raised $125,000.
In 1986, the brewpub opened at 1339 NW Flanders Street in an old creamery building in Northwest Portland; they only produced draft beer. In 1988, they began bottling their flagship Portland Ale in 32-ounce package and in 1989 began bottling it as a 12-ounce 6-pack. In 1991, Tony Adams and Mac and Scott MacTarnahan invested capital in the brewery, and that same year the company embarked on an ambitious financial plan to build a new brewery. In 1992, they expanded their distribution network to the seven western states and won a gold medal at the Great American Beer Festival with MacTarnahan’s Ale.
With a growing market and need for increased production, in 1992, they purchased brewing equipment from Sixenbräu in Nördlingen, Germany, including copper brewing vessels, and began production of a new brewery at 2730 NW 31st Avenue with an expected 65,000-barrel annual capacity, which was more than double the production at the Flanders facility. The new brewery met its full production level in 1993. In spring of 1995, Portland Brewing purchased and installed a new state of the art bottling line from Krones Inc., which could rinse, fill, cap, and label up to 250 bottles a minute, roughly twice the amount of the old line. With the addition of equipment and increased tank space, by 1995 the brewing capacity was 100,000 barrels annually and by 1996 was 135,000 barrels.
The company embarked on several campaigns to raise money for expansion and renovation projects. In 1992, the company offered 100,000 shares of common stock to Oregon residents (which sold in 32 days); the next year, they offered an additional 100,000 shares to Oregon and Washington residents (which sold in 60 days). These two offerings raised $1 million. In 1994, they offered an additional 490,000 shares to finance increased production capabilities, marketing efforts, and German style beer hall and restaurant; they raised $2.8 million. In 1995, they raised $2.9 million, which brought the total number of shareholders to approximately 5,500, number of outstanding shares to 2.1 million, and the total dollars raised by investors to almost $7 million. The NW Flanders Street facility was remodeled in summer 1996 and a new kitchen was added.
By 1998 the company was in financial trouble and MacTarnahan bought $3.5 million in debt in exchange for stock; as a result, Portland Brewing began using MacTarnahan labeling. Portland Brewing Company merged with Saxer Brewing Company of Lake Oswego in 2000.
Hart Brewing and Pyramid Breweries
Hart Brewing was founded by Beth Hartwell and Tom Baune in Kalama, Washington in 1984; the name of the brewery was a contraction of Hartwell. Five investors from Seattle acquired Hart Brewing in 1989 and then purchased Thomas Kemper Brewing Company from Poulsbo, Washington in 1992. They also moved to a new, larger facility in 1992 and by 1994, Hart Brewing was the fourth largest craft brewery in the United States. In 1995, Hart Brewing opened a new brewery in Seattle, known as the Seattle Alehouse (closed in 2020). Also in 1995, the company became a publicly traded company on the NASDAQ exchange, issuing 2.6 million shares. The name was changed to Pyramid Breweries in 1996. In 1997, Pyramid Brewery opened a brewing facility and restaurant in Berkeley, California (closed in 2015).
Hart Brewing’s first beer was Pyramid Pale ale, and it was followed in 1985 by Pyramid Wheaten Ale, the first year-round wheat beer made in America since Prohibition. Pyramid Snow Cap Ale was released in 1986. They began making a Hefeweizen in 1993 and an Apricot Ale in 1994.
Portland Brewing and Pyramid Breweries
In 2004, MacTarnahan, then 88 years old, sold the Portland Brewing Company to Pyramid Breweries of Seattle. The Portland Brewing facility was renamed “MacTarnahan's Brewing Company.” MacTarnahan died later that year.
In 2008, Pyramid Breweries was acquired by Magic Hat Brewing Company, which was subsequently bought by North American Breweries of Rochester, New York in 2010. In 2012, the company was purchased by the Costa Rican company Florida Ice & Farm Co. In 2013, the brewery announced it would return to the Portland Brewing Company name.
After declining revenue, the company closed the Portland taproom and restaurant in 2018 and ceased production entirely in 2021.
Hart Brewing, Inc.; Pyramid Breweries, Inc.; Hart Brewing, Inc.; Portland Brewing Company.; Pyramid Breweries, Inc.
Ephemera (general object genre); Photographic prints.; Scrapbooks.
Kalama (Wash.); Portland (Or.); Seattle (Wash.)
Beer industry--United States--History.; Beer--Oregon--Portland--History.; Brewing industry--Oregon.; Brewing.; Microbreweries--United States.
Businesses and Corporations; Advertising and Marketing; Women; Oregon; Washington (State); Portland; Photographs; Scrapbooks
These materials were donated to the Special Collections and Archives Research Center by Ryan Pappe in 2021.
Collection is open for research.
The Portland Brewing Collection is complemented by several other collections. The Fred Bowman Papers feature digital surrogates of papers and photographs documenting the creation and expansion of one Portland Brewing Company. The Art Larrance Collection, including digital surrogates of articles of incorporation for Portland Brewing, company newsletters, and pre-Prohibition hops and brewing advertising and company materials (items in this collection have been digitized and are available online.)
The Oregon Hops and Brewing Archives Oral History Collection (OH 35) includes interviews from industry professionals, journalists, and community members. Notable are interviews with Portland Brewing founders Fred Bowman and Art Larrance, Hart Brewing founder Beth Hartwell, and brewers Ryan Pappe and Doug Hodges.
The Fred Eckhardt Papers include photographs and research files for Portland Brewing, Hart Brewing, and Pyramid Breweries. The Brewing and Fermentation Research Collection (MSS BFRC) contains information pertaining to the Pacific Northwest brewing industry; included are newsletters for homebrew clubs, ephemera, news clippings, and noteworthy industry publications.
Further information regarding the values, logistics, and goals of the burgeoning regional brewing community can be found in organizational collections like the Heart of the Valley Homebrewers Records, Ninkasi Brewing Company Collection (MSS Ninkasi), McMenamins Brewery Collection, and the Oregon Brewers Guild Records. The personal research collections of Denny Conn, Pete Dunlop, Abram Goldman-Armstrong, and Robert Daly contain additional information regarding the beer writing process and beer culture.
Collections linked to Oregon State University research, as well as other manuscript collections, are described on the Oregon Hops and Brewing Archives research guide. More information pertaining to the history of hop growing and brewing in Oregon can be found on the Oregon Hops and Brewing Archives website.
The Portland Brewing Company records are arranged into four series: 1. Brewing Records, 1993-2021; 2. Portland Brewing Company, 1991-2014; 3. Hart Brewing, 1984-1993; 4. Pyramid Breweries, 1997-2010.
The Portland Brewing Company Records includes brewing records, photographs, promotional and training materials, and ephemera.
The bulk of the collection is in Series 1, Brewing Records. These are arranged chronologically and by type of record. There are a few exceptions for early Hart Brewing beers, but most of these records document production at the Portland facility. However, the name of the company and the title of the forms changed several times, and that is reflected on the folder titles.
Series 2 through 4 are organized by company. The Portland Brewing Company materials include photographs of facilities, events, and equipment; marketing, promotional, packaging items; news clippings; building plans; and training materials. The Hart Brewing Company materials include marketing and promotional items, as well as a scrapbook with photographs, correspondence, ephemera, and news clippings. The Pyramid Breweries, Inc. materials include marketing and promotional items, news clippings, and a training manual.
- Brewing Records, 1993-2021; Series 1
  The brew house and cellar logs record data about ingredients, temperatures, waste, and other measurements of the brewing process and when the beer is in storage. A Bright Tank is a tank used to hold beer in preparation for packaging; the term “bright” refers to “bright beer,” which is beer that has been rendered clear by filtration, centrifugation, fining, and/or maturation. Pilot brewing systems are the secondary systems used by breweries; typically, they produce a fraction of the beer compared to the main system and are used for experimenting with new styles or ingredients. Of note is the Pyramid Breweries recipe archive, Pyramid beer lab reports, and the Craft Brand trademark portfolio (Dundee, Magic Hat, Portland Brewing, Pyramid) and includes beer information sheets and marketing materials.
  - Brew sheets and cellar sheets, 1993 (Box-folder 1.01)
    Number 001-049
  - Brew sheets and cellar sheets, 1993 (Box-folder 1.02)
    Number 050-114
  - Brew sheets and cellar sheets, 1994 (Box-folder 1.03)
    Number 115-121, 001-049
  - Brew sheets and cellar sheets, 1994 (Box-folder 1.04)
    Number 053-099
  - Brew sheets and cellar sheets, 1994 (Box-folder 1.05)
    Number 100-149
  - Brew sheets and cellar sheets, 1994 (Box-folder 1.06)
    Number 150-199
  - Brew sheets and cellar sheets, 1994 (Box-folder 1.07)
    Number 200-249
  - Brew sheets and cellar sheets, 1994 (Box-folder 1.08)
    Number 250-326
  - Brew sheets and cellar sheets, 1995 (Box-folder 1.09)
    Number 001-149
  - Brew sheets and cellar sheets, 1995 (Box-folder 1.10)
    Number 050-149
  - Brew sheets and cellar sheets, 1995 (Box-folder 1.11)
    Number 150-249
  - Brew sheets and cellar sheets, 1995 (Box-folder 1.12)
    Number 250-349
  - Brew sheets and cellar sheets, 1995 (Box-folder 1.13)
    Number 350-449
  - Brew sheets and cellar sheets, 1995 (Box-folder 1.14)
    Number 450-553
  - Brew sheets and cellar sheets, 1996 (Box-folder 1.15)
    Number 001-099
  - Brew sheets and cellar sheets, 1996 (Box-folder 1.16)
    Number 100-199
  - Brew sheets and cellar sheets, 1996 (Box-folder 2.01)
    Number 285-349
  - Brew sheets and cellar sheets, 1996 (Box-folder 2.02)
  - Brew sheets and cellar sheets, 1996 (Box-folder 2.03)
    Number 450-499
  - Brew sheets and cellar sheets, 1996 (Box-folder 2.04)
    Number 500-596
  - Brewhouse reports, 1997 (Box-folder 2.05)
  - Brewhouse reports, 1997 (Box-folder 2.06)
  - Brewhouse reports, 1997 (Box-folder 2.07)
    Number 200-299
  - Brewhouse reports, 1997 (Box-folder 2.08)
    Number 300-358
  - Brewhouse reports, 1998 (Box-folder 2.09)
  - Brewhouse reports, 1998 (Box-folder 2.10)
  - Brewhouse reports, 1998 (Box-folder 2.11)
  - Brewhouse reports, 1998 (Box-folder 2.12)
    Number 300-399
  - Brewhouse reports, 1998 (Box-folder 2.13)
    Number 400-450
  - Brewhouse reports, 1999 (Box-folder 2.14)
    Number 001-199
  - Brewhouse reports, 1999 (Box-folder 2.15)
  - Brewhouse reports and cellar sheets, 1999 (Box-folder 2.16)
  - Brewhouse reports and cellar sheets, 1999 (Box-folder 3.01)
  - Brewhouse reports and cellar sheets, 1999 (Box-folder 3.02)
    Number 400-497
  - Brewhouse reports and cellar sheets, 2000 (Box-folder 3.03)
  - Brewhouse reports and cellar sheets, 2000 (Box-folder 3.04)
  - Brewhouse reports and cellar sheets, 2000 (Box-folder 3.05)
  - Brewhouse reports and cellar sheets, 2000 (Box-folder 3.06)
  - Brewhouse reports and cellar sheets, 2000 (Box-folder 3.07)
    Number 400-449
  - Brewhouse reports and cellar sheets, 2000 (Box-folder 3.08)
  - Brewhouse reports and cellar sheets, 2000 (Box-folder 3.09)
    Number 500-580
  - Brewhouse reports and cellar sheets, 2001 (Box-folder 3.10)
  - Brewhouse reports and cellar sheets, 2001 (Box-folder 3.11)
  - Brewhouse reports and cellar sheets, 2001 (Box-folder 3.12)
  - Brewhouse reports and cellar sheets, 2001 (Box-folder 3.13)
  - Brewhouse reports and cellar sheets, 2001 (Box-folder 3.14)
  - Brewhouse reports and cellar sheets, 2001 (Box-folder 3.15)
    Number 450-531
  - Brewhouse reports and cellar sheets, 2002 (Box-folder 4.01)
  - Brewhouse reports and cellar sheets, 2002 (Box-folder 4.02)
  - Brewhouse reports and cellar sheets, 2002 (Box-folder 4.03)
  - Brewhouse reports and cellar sheets, 2002 (Box-folder 4.04)
  - Brewhouse reports and cellar sheets, 2002 (Box-folder 4.05)
    Number 401-443
  - Pyramid brewhouse reports and cellar sheets, 2002 (Box-folder 4.06)
    Number 229-349
  - Pyramid brewhouse reports and cellar sheets, 2002 (Box-folder 4.07)
    Number 350-435
  - Pyramid Breweries, Inc. brewhouse reports, 2005 (Box-folder 4.08)
  - Pyramid Breweries, Inc. brewhouse reports, 2005 (Box-folder 4.09)
    Number 200-399
  - Pyramid Breweries, Inc. brewhouse reports, 2005 (Box-folder 4.10)
    Number 400-599
  - Pyramid Breweries, Inc. brewhouse reports, 2005 (Box-folder 4.11)
    Number 600-750
  - Pyramid Breweries, Inc. brewhouse reports, 2009 (Box-folder 4.12)
  - Pyramid Breweries, Inc. brewhouse reports, 2009 (Box-folder 4.13)
  - Pyramid Breweries, Inc. brewhouse reports, 2009 (Box-folder 4.14)
  - Pyramid Breweries, Inc. brewhouse reports, 2009 (Box-folder 4.15)
    Number 600-753
  - Pyramid Breweries, Inc. brewhouse reports, 2010 (Box-folder 5.01)
  - Pyramid Breweries, Inc. brewhouse reports, 2010 (Box-folder 5.02)
  - Pyramid Breweries, Inc. brewhouse reports, 2010 (Box-folder 5.03)
  - Pyramid Breweries, Inc. brewhouse reports, 2010 (Box-folder 5.04)
    Number 600-786
  - Pyramid Breweries, Inc. brewhouse reports, 2011 (Box-folder 5.05)
  - Pyramid Breweries, Inc. brewhouse reports, 2011 (Box-folder 5.06)
  - Pyramid Breweries, Inc. brewhouse reports, 2011 (Box-folder 5.07)
  - Pyramid Breweries, Inc. brewhouse reports, 2011 (Box-folder 5.08)
    Number 600-763
  - Pyramid Breweries, Inc. brewhouse reports, 2012 (Box-folder 5.09)
  - Pyramid Breweries, Inc. brewhouse reports, 2012 (Box-folder 5.10)
  - Pyramid Breweries, Inc. brewhouse reports, 2012 (Box-folder 5.11)
  - Pyramid Breweries, Inc. brewhouse reports, 2012 (Box-folder 5.12)
    Number 600-775
  - Pyramid Breweries, Inc. brewhouse reports, 2013 (Box-folder 5.13)
  - Pyramid Breweries, Inc. brewhouse reports, 2013 (Box-folder 6.01)
    Number 200-398
  - Portland Brewing brewhouse reports, 2013 (Box-folder 6.02)
    Number 399-599
  - Portland Brewing brewhouse reports, 2013 (Box-folder 6.03)
    Number 600-854
  - Portland Brewing brewhouse reports, 2014 (Box-folder 6.04)
  - Portland Brewing brewhouse reports, 2014 (Box-folder 6.05)
  - Portland Brewing brewhouse reports, 2014 (Box-folder 6.06)
  - Portland Brewing brewhouse reports, 2014 (Box-folder 6.07)
    Number 600-799
  - Portland Brewing brewhouse reports, 2014 (Box-folder 6.08)
    Number 800-1028
  - Portland Brewing bright tank logs, 2015 (Box-folder 6.09)
    January through March.
  - Portland Brewing bright tank logs, 2015 (Box-folder 6.10)
    April through June.
  - Portland Brewing bright tank logs, 2015 (Box-folder 6.11)
    July through September.
  - Portland Brewing bright tank logs, 2015 (Box-folder 6.12)
    October through December.
  - Portland Brewing cellar sheets, 2015 (Box-folder 6.13)
    Number 001-251
  - Portland Brewing cellar sheets, 2015 (Box-folder 6.14)
    Number 252-503
  - Portland Brewing cellar sheets, 2015 (Box-folder 6.15)
    Number 504-750
  - Portland Brewing cellar sheets, 2015 (Box-folder 6.16)
    Number 751-951
  - Portland Brewing Company fermentation and cellar logs, 2015 (Box-folder 6.17)
  - Pyramid Portland daily transfer log, 2015 (Box-folder 7.01)
  - Portland Brewing brew sheets, 2015 (Box-folder 7.02)
  - Portland Brewing brew sheets, 2015 (Box-folder 7.03)
  - Portland Brewing brew sheets, 2015 (Box-folder 7.04)
  - Portland Brewing brew sheets, 2015 (Box-folder 7.05)
  - Portland Brewing brew sheets, 2015 (Box-folder 7.06)
    Number 800-951
  - Portland Brewing brew sheets, 2015 (Box-folder 7.07)
    Pilot brews
  - Pyramid Portland bright tank logs, 2016 (Box-folder 7.08)
  - Pyramid Portland bright tank logs, 2016 (Box-folder 7.09)
  - Pyramid Portland bright tank logs, 2016 (Box-folder 7.10)
  - Pyramid Portland bright tank logs, 2016 (Box-folder 7.11)
  - Portland Brewing cellar sheets, 2016 (Box-folder 7.12)
    Number 001-202
  - Portland Brewing cellar sheets, 2016 (Box-folder 7.13)
    Number 203-499
  - Portland Brewing cellar sheets, 2016 (Box-folder 7.14)
    Number 500-782
  - Portland Brewing fermentation and cellar logs, 2016 (Box-folder 7.15)
  - Portland Brewing brew sheets, 2016 (Box-folder 7.16)
  - Portland Brewing brew sheets, 2016 (Box-folder 7.17)
  - Portland Brewing brew sheets, 2016 (Box-folder 7.18)
  - Portland Brewing brew sheets, 2016 (Box-folder 8.01)
    Number 600-782
  - Portland Brewing brew sheets, 2016 (Box-folder 8.02)
  - Pyramid Breweries bright tank logs, 2017 (Box-folder 8.03)
  - Pyramid Breweries bright tank logs, 2017 (Box-folder 8.04)
  - Pyramid Breweries bright tank logs, 2017 (Box-folder 8.05)
  - Pyramid Breweries bright tank logs, 2017 (Box-folder 8.06)
  - Portland Brewing cellar sheets, 2017 (Box-folder 8.07)
  - Portland Brewing cellar sheets, 2017 (Box-folder 8.08)
    Number 203-398
  - Portland Brewing cellar sheets, 2017 (Box-folder 8.09)
    Number 400-676
  - Portland Brewing brew sheets, 2017 (Box-folder 8.10)
  - Portland Brewing brew sheets, 2017 (Box-folder 8.11)
  - Portland Brewing brew sheets, 2017 (Box-folder 8.12)
  - Portland Brewing brew sheets, 2017 (Box-folder 8.13)
    Number 600-676
  - Pyramid Portland daily transfer forms, 2017 (Box-folder 8.14)
  - Portland Brewing brew and cellar sheets, 2017 (Box-folder 8.15)
  - Portland Brewing fermentation and cellar sheets, 2017 (Box-folder 8.16)
  - Pyramid Breweries bright tank logs, 2018 (Box-folder 8.17)
  - Pyramid Breweries bright tank logs, 2018 (Box-folder 8.18)
  - Pyramid Breweries bright tank logs, 2018 (Box-folder 8.19)
  - Pyramid Breweries bright tank logs, 2018 (Box-folder 8.20)
  - Portland Brewing cellar sheets, 2018 (Box-folder 9.01)
    Number 001-300
  - Portland Brewing cellar sheets, 2018 (Box-folder 9.02)
    Number 301-588
  - Portland Brewing brew sheets, 2018 (Box-folder 9.03)
  - Portland Brewing brew sheets, 2018 (Box-folder 9.04)
  - Portland Brewing brew sheets, 2018 (Box-folder 9.05)
    Number 400-588
  - Pyramid Portland daily transfer forms, 2018 (Box-folder 9.06)
  - Portland Brewing pilot brew and cellar sheets, 2018 (Box-folder 9.07)
  - Portland Brewing fermentations sheets, 2018 (Box-folder 9.08)
  - Pyramid Breweries bright tank logs, 2019 (Box-folder 9.09)
  - Pyramid Breweries bright tank logs, 2019 (Box-folder 9.10)
  - Pyramid Breweries bright tank logs, 2019 (Box-folder 9.11)
  - Pyramid Breweries bright tank logs, 2019 (Box-folder 9.12)
  - Portland Brewing cellar sheets, 2019 (Box-folder 9.13)
    Number 001-250
  - Portland Brewing cellar sheets, 2019 (Box-folder 9.14)
    Number 251-451
  - Portland Brewing brew sheets, 2019 (Box-folder 9.15)
  - Portland Brewing brew sheets, 2019 (Box-folder 9.16)
    Number 200-451
  - Pyramid Portland daily transfer forms, 2019 (Box-folder 9.17)
  - Portland Brewing pilot brews and cellar sheets, 2019 (Box-folder 9.18)
  - Portland Brewing fermentation sheets, 2019 (Box-folder 9.19)
  - Pyramid Breweries bright tank logs, 2020-2021 (Box-folder 10.01)
  - Pyramid Breweries bright tank logs, 2020 (Box-folder 10.02)
  - Pyramid Breweries bright tank logs, 2020 (Box-folder 10.03)
    July through October.
  - Pyramid Breweries bright tank logs, 2020-2021 (Box-folder 10.04)
    October through February.
  - Portland Brewing cellar sheets, 2020 (Box-folder 10.05)
    Number 001-150
  - Portland Brewing cellar sheets, 2020 (Box-folder 10.06)
    Number 151-304
  - Portland Brewing brew sheets, 2020 (Box-folder 10.07)
  - Portland Brewing brew sheets, 2020 (Box-folder 10.08)
    Number 150-305
  - Portland Brewing pilot brew and cellar sheets, 2020-2021 (Box-folder 10.09)
  - Portland Brewing fermentation sheets, 2020-2021 (Box-folder 10.10)
  - Portland Brewing brew sheets, 2021 (Box-folder 10.11)
    Number 001-010
  - Pyramid Breweries recipe archive, 2003-2007 (Box-folder 10.12)
  - Pyramid Breweries recipe archive, 2004-2007 (Box-folder 10.13)
  - Pyramid beer lab reports, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 10.14)
    Wheaten, Apricot, Hefeweizen, Pale Ale, Kalsch, Kolsch, Snow Cap, Porter, Stout, B. Brown, Rye Ale.
  - Pyramid Pale Ale, 1990-1995 (Box-folder 10.15)
    Brewing lab reports, correspondence, lab reports.
  - Pyramid Brewing Kalama, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 10.16)
    Brewing audit, correspondence, hop rub spreadsheet.
  - Craft Brand trademark portfolio, 2014 (Box-folder 10.17)
    Dundee and Magic Hat.
  - Craft Brand trademark portfolio, 2014 (Box-folder 10.18)
    Portland Brewing and Pyramid.
- Portland Brewing Company, 1991-2014; Series 2
  Pictures of equipment, packaging, parties, and equipment; reports for brew house; marketing and promotional items such as coasters, labels, posters, and packaging; building plans and drawings; and news clippings.
  - Photographs, 1993-1999 (Box-folder 10.19)
    Pictures of equipment, packaging, parties, and equipment. Of note is the installation of a bright tank; beer filtration system equipment from Germany; Portland Brewing grand opening party; original installation of system from Sixenbräu in Nördlingen, Germany; and the installation of a 520-barrel tank (accessed through a cut out in the wall). 42 pictures total.
  - Brew house and marketing reports, 1991-1997 (Box-folder 10.20)
  - Marketing and promotional items, 1994-2005 (Box-folder 10.21)
  - Newspaper clippings and company newsletter, 1992-2014 (Box-folder 10.22)
  - Training manual, 2000 (Box-folder 10.23)
  - Packaging, 2010 (Box-folder 10.24)
  - Building plans and promotional materials, 1992-1996 (Map-folder 1)